on today's video we're going to make Ben
and& Jerry's Cherry Garcia using Frozen
cherries and this is being made in the
Ninja
creamy mapon gets tighter every week
anyway we got a couple of things we need
to do for Cherry Garcia there were two
different versions there's the North
American version and the European
version European version has chocolate
pieces with cherry and cherry ice cream
and the North American version has fudge
pieces it's likely just a wording you
couldn't get it back in or it's not been
available in in England and far as I'm
away the rest of Europe for many many
years so I never actually tried that
version but what we're going to do is
we're going to prepare the cherries
first because we don't want those to
freeze solid in this mix so we're going
to take a small
pan and only use that arrol has in ice
cream freezing point
depression so what we're going to do is
we're going to open our
cherries these are huge and we're going
to get 100 G of cherries in our pan here
these cherries are for the adding not
for making the base all right
so with our cherries in here we're going
to add in about 150 g of water
like
so and this is arrol monk fruit combo
it's terrible ice cream because it goes
it recrystallizes within 24 hours so you
get this uh weird kind
of I have no spoons left so I'm going to
use this you get this
weird Ice Crystal sugar crystal kind of
thing going on it's terrible stuff to
use but what we going to do is we're
going to put into this mixture
here 60 G of that if you just have arrol
that is fine monk fruit sugar on its own
won't do this we want the arrol part of
this you can do this with Xylitol that
will have the same effect Stevia pure
stevia that will have the same effect
Stevia is two to 300 times as sweet as
sugar the effect on freezing point is
massive so what we're doing here is
literally just creating a sugar syrup I
mean it's sugar-free you know we're
creating a sugar syrup that we're just
going to gently
warm on the hob and Infuse those
cherries with it so let's just get on a
hob ticking over on low for about 20
minutes the point of that heating phase
is to allow the Cherry flesh protein
proteins to expand to allow that sugar
syrup to be infused within it it will
stop them going super
icy it's really difficult to stop fruit
going icy and ice cream this is one of
the only ways to really do it
successfully so with that in mind let's
get on to the ice cream so like I said
we're going to do this in the Ninja
creamy you can absolutely do this in
your standard ice cream machine it will
turn out slightly better because you'll
get overrun in it as well um but you
also get that super fudgy kind of
texture in the creamy which is delicious
so with that in mind I'm going to need a
spoon spoon
so let's start off with our basic
ingredients our milk and our
cream so I'm going to flash up on the
screen here screenshots from Ben and
Jerry's website this is North American
website um or American webite website I
should
say and from these numbers we can
actually see that it starts with or the
ice cream the tub of ice
cream based on the weight which they
have kindly now changed 149 G per Ser
per serving if you will that ice cream
tub carries 14% fat and like 24 to 25%
sugar which is insanely high now
understanding the breakdown of that
really difficult basically impossible we
don't know where that sugar is we don't
know whether it's in the cherries in the
ice cream base in the fudge a combin
it's going to be a combination of all
three we don't know how much of each one
so what we're going to do is we're going
to bring this sugar level down we're
going to bring it down to about 15 and 1
12 to
15.8% that's in line with what we expect
from a standard Luxury Ice Cream in
North America and Europe so to get to
that you are going to need 375 G of 2%
milk if you only use whole milk don't
stress about it just use that 375 into
that we're going to use 600 G of cream
this is 33% whipping cream if you only
have 36% you can use that it will boost
the Frat content a little bit so maybe
just drop it down by 50 g anyway 600 so
we're already starting off with a nice
luxury recipe here uh I do get people
saying oh you only make high fat high
sugar ice creams that is not true you
obviously only watched one video and
thought you'd comment on it I'm make a
variation of ice creams anywhere from 4%
fat up to 20% fat and zero sugar up to
about 25% sugar everything in between so
if you want to use a sugar substitute
you can if you want to use alos in this
recipe you absolutely can you probably
have to reduce the amount by about 10%
xylol you'd have to reduce it
considerably because of the freezing
point ariol don't use it we need 190 g
of sugar this is a big batch if you're
wondering I'm making 1.5 L here three
tubs of ninja creamy I'm making that
size because I'm going to make some in
here and I'm going to make some in my
traditional ice cream machine too let's
weigh some of these out cuz I'm going to
use a stabilizer in this fruit based ice
creams it's it's quite important to use
a stabilizer because they carry a lot of
water and we need to make sure 190 G we
need to make sure that we are dealing
with that free water so that it doesn't
create an an icy finish I'm going to use
today an off-the-shelf ice cream
stabilizer from special
ingredients this is a
mix of standard stabilizers and
emulsifiers it's really good stuff you
can use it in gelato and sbet and ice
cream and whatever else stir your
stabilizer into your sugar if you're not
using stabilizer then just
don't so we've got that there we are
going to need skim milk powder we are
going to need how much we going to need
we're going to need 110 G of skim milk
powder skin milk powder we're going to
need invert sugar so we're going to use
corn syrup in this corn syrup we're
going to need 30 G of our invert
sugar and two 100 G of
cherries what we can do is put our
cherries in here once everything else
has gone in so let's load up
our pan we got a nice big pan
here so we can put our sugar with our
stabilizer in here just get it mixed
in what you're just Distributing that
Sugar you're starting to allow it to
dissolve just so it doesn't stick to
anything it's not super important and
we're going to add in our milk
powder again we just don't want it to
sit on the top cuz we're going to add
the cherries in in a second and that
corn syrup so just having a nice plain
liquid to add those into makes life much
easier like that 30
G of corn syrup the corn syrup has or
invert sugar whatever one you want to
use has an effect on the freezing point
and the texture the ice cream and now
we're going to add
in 200 g of Frozen
cherries the cheapest of the cheap
cherries from Safeway I think they were
they're huge so the likelihood is they
are bing cherries that's
clean right now with all of those
ingredients on there we're going to put
it on the hob and bring this up to 85c
185 F activate our stabilizer and that
will also allow the cherries to break
down the sugars to break down the sugars
have already broken down because it's
been they've been frozen but we're also
allowing the physical breakdown of the
flesh to allow that water from the
cherries to completely come out
integrate with our other liquid so let's
get on hob so we've got two things going
on here we've got our arthriti sugar
syrup infusing into our cherries so that
Heat's coming up nicely now we can turn
that off and just leave that to sit
there until it's completely cooled down
and in here we have our ice cream base
so let me Center that up onto the shop
so we've got our cherries in here
they're still
Frozen We There are a few ways to make
cherry ice
cream with real cherries the problem
you're going to have in some variations
is it's a super acidic fruit so if
you're not careful it's going to curdle
your mixture by doing this we avoid all
of that situation because slowly the
leech out stops that curdling
possibility curdling usually happens
when a an acidic compound blends with
dairy at a set temperature you can
avoid curdling by changing your approach
to
temperature if you have a hot acidic
syrup and you put it into cold Dairy
it's going to curdle there's two things
there that are going to make a curdle
the heat differential and obviously the
acid iic difference if you were to cool
your acidic liquid down and then add it
to your cold Dairy when it's cold itself
much less likely to curdle at that stage
and then bring it up to temperature
together so that's what we're doing here
we're adding everything cold and we're
bringing this up to temperature we want
to be careful the moment you start
getting over about 90 Centigrade you do
run the risk of curdling so we need to
be careful and keep an eye on this get
your laser the moment your sugar
thermometer whatever you've got get it
out you're going to need it so let's
come back once we're up to temperature
we're pretty much there now so what we
can do is turn the heat
off and move on with the next
stage so the next stage is to blend it
all together because we want this cherry
base to be a clean base so we don't
really want that many pieces of this
Cherry flesh in there we've got the
flavor out of it already so let's put a
whole lot into
our blender this is super hot liquid so
just please be careful
and let's blend this all up we're doing
this to get all that flavor out of those
cherries just do on low to start with
for about 20
seconds and and we can have a look
there's still quite a few flexs in there
so we're going to go on to medium maybe
even high for you know little 5c 10
second bests
there we go let's have a look see how
we're getting
on really nice
natural cherry
flavor put that
there if you get lots of bits you don't
have a blender mash up your cherries
with whatever you have to hand a fork a
potato masher anything like that and
then run it through a fine mesh Sie we
don't want huge chunks Cherry because
we're dealing with the cherries in a
separate container so now that our base
is done we
can get our
tubs and put it
in there we
go like I say I'm making this in two
machines
so lovely color let me know in the
comments if you have seen the color
difference on B and Jerry's Tubs on
their website and it originally used to
be a nice pink color ice cream base now
it's kind of this Bland almost brown
color ice cream really weird makes you
wonder how they're getting the cherry
flavor in
there right our base is done we can put
this oh it tastes
good come
on we can put this one in the freezer
and we're going to put this one in the
fridge right with that bit done we've
got one final step and that's to make
our chocolate fudge so quick tidy up and
I'll come
back right our ice cream base is in the
fridge it's chilling down it's going to
take you know a good few hours to chill
down so we've got our Cherry mixture
here with our arral sugar syrup we're
going to let that cool down and splash
everywhere in the refrigerator we can't
use that sugar syrup for anything that
has an effect on freezing you can use it
in baking and cooking if you want
absolutely you're going to get this kind
of like Cherry infused sugar syrup it's
a sugar-free syrup so anyway this will
go in the fridge quick clean up of the
pan because we're going to make fudge
super easy fudge recipe it needs a can
of condensed milk this is the 390 G 300
ML and
350 g of
chocolate we need that much chocolate
cuz that's what's going to set this so
everything goes in a pan and we'll get
it on the hob we are simply going to mix
all of this together until the chocolate
is completely melted and our mixture is
a luscious smooth silky liquid once your
chocolate has melted and it's become
this lovely smooth
silky consistency we'll take it off the
heat and don't super heat this you want
to warm it gently if you have the heat
too high you're going to burn the
chocolate but now that we've got that
we're going to put this in a lined
baking tray this is a 12 by 8 baking
tray the chocolate I'm using is Cacao
Barry 70% use a darker chocolate don't
use milk chocolate doesn't work
particularly well with cherries so in
this goes into here does make a a large
amount of fudge this stuff keeps forever
in the freezer
um I had some in the freezer for well
over a year back in the UK and it was
perfectly usable
still so yes this is a lot but if you
like using fudge and ice cream this is
like a good year Supply or 5 minutes if
it's me with that done we can just leave
this out a room temperature to set our
ice cream base is chilling our cherries
are chilling in the fridge too so all we
got to do is sit back and wait a few
hours for everything to be
[Music]
ready right couple of things we need to
do before we look at
that ice yeah ice on the Bott couple of
things we need to do before we get our
Ben and& Jerry's Cherry Garcia going in
here we need to chop up some of our
fudge and prepare our cherries so all
we're going to do here is is take some
of our fudge nice and
hard chop it up into small pieces we
can't put big pieces in the Ninja cream
just doesn't have the power to process
that down to be fair there aren't many
ice cream machines that do have the
power to do that so we're going to cut
these up into about half CM
pieces and we also need to take a couple
of our cherries so these have been sat
in the fridge actually overnight this is
still in the arrol sugar
syrup so we're just going to chop these
up into quarters now it's time to get
our ice cream out of freezer spin it on
your ice cream setting like
normal so we got a nice
pink ice cream going on here natural
color we're going to use a spoon down in
the center all the way to the bottom you
know the score if you've got any nin
creamy some of our fudge some of our
Cherry get it in there back in we
go benon Jerry's Cherry Garcia in your
Ninja creamy get some dished up in a
bowl so you can see how this turned
out super delicious creamy ice cream we
got our Flex of cherry and chocolate in
there couple of pieces for decoration
nice cherry on
top and
absolutely
delicious right dished up put this one
back in the freezer again will last a
good while in the
freezer let's eat
some
yeah you are welcome Ben and& Jerry's
Cherry Garcia
the OG version the pink ice cream
version not the weird brown taupey color
that it is
now super delicious natural Cherry ice
cream perfect textured fudge not too
hard not too
soft delicious soft cherries
throughout absolutely
incredible it's surprisingly easy to
make it will last in your freezer as
well you can take a scoop or two put it
back in don't have to worry about it
turning into a block of ice this will
work in your standard ice cream machine
2 hope you enjoyed this one thanks very
much for watching don't forget to like
And subscribe got lots of ninja creamy
recipes coming in the future lots of Ben
and& Jerry remakes lots of hundar
remakes van Luan ample Hills all of them
so don't forget to like And
subscribe see you next time
[Music]